# **Brendan Kennedy**

https://brendankennedy.org
Google Scholar

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/brendan-kennedy-usc/

https://github.com/BrendanKennedy

I am a 5<sup>th</sup> year computer science Ph.D. student at USC studying explainable NLP and text analysis with Morteza Dehghani. My research focuses on ways to measure theoretical constructs in natural language and developing resources — teaching, software, and applied research — for language analysis in psychology.

### **Education**

2016 – present Ph.D., Computer Science, University of Southern California

Advisor: Morteza Dehghani, Ph.D.

Research Topic: Explainable NLP and Text Analysis Methods

2012 – 2016 **B.S. Computer Science, Gonzaga University** Magna cum Laude

Minors: Mathematics and Philosophy

## **Research Publications**

### **Book Chapters**

**Kennedy**, **B.**, Ashokkumar, A., Boyd, R., & Dehghani, M. (forthcoming). Text analysis for psychology: Methods, principles, and practices (M. Dehghani & R. Boyd, Eds.). In M. Dehghani & R. Boyd (Eds.), *The Atlas of Language Analysis in Psychology*. Guilford Press. **6** https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/h2b8t

#### **Preprints, Under Review & Under Revision**

- **Kennedy**, **B.**, Atari, M., Mostafazadeh Davani, A., Hoover, J., Omrani, A., Graham, J., & Dehghani, M. (R&R at Cognition). Moral Concerns are Differentially Observable in Language. PsyArXiv.

   https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/uqmty
- **Kennedy**, **B.**, Atari, M., Mostafazadeh Davani, A., Yeh, L., Omrani, A., Kim, Y., Coombs Jr., K., Havaldar, S., Portillo-Wightman, G., Gonzalez, E., Hoover, J., Azatian, A., Cardenas, G., Hussain, A., Lara, A., Omary, A., Park, C., Wang, X., Wijaya, C., ... Dehghani, M. (R&R at Language Resources and Evaluation). The Gab Hate Corpus: A Collection of 27k Posts Annotated for Hate Speech. PsyArXiv.

  \*https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/hqjxn
- Hoover, J., Atari, M., Mostafazadeh Davani\*, A., **Kennedy**\*, **B.**, Portillo-Wightman, G., Yeh, L., Kogon, D., & Dehghani, M. (R&R at Nature Communications). Bound in Hatred: The role of group-based morality in acts of hate. PsyArXiv. https://psyarxiv.com/359me/
- Mostafazadeh Davani, A., Omrani, A., **Kennedy**, **B.**, Atari, M., Ren, X., & Dehghani, M. (under review). Fair Hate Speech Detection through Evaluation of Social Group Counterfactuals. Ohttps://arxiv.org/abs/2010.12779

## **Conference Proceedings**

- Jin, X., Barbieri, F., **Kennedy**, **B.**, Mostafazadeh Davani, A., Neves, L., & Ren, X. (2021). On Transferability of Bias Mitigation Effects in Language Model Fine-Tuning, In *The 2021 annual conference of the north american chapter of the association for computational linguistics (accepted).*
- **Kennedy\***, **B.**, Jin\*, X., Mostafazadeh Davani, A., Dehghani, M., & Ren, X. (2020). Contextualizing hate speech classifiers with post-hoc explanation, In *Proceedings of the 2020 Annual Conference of the Association for Computational Linguistics*. **6** https://www.aclweb.org/anthology/2020.acl-main.483/

- Mostafazadeh Davani, A., Yeh, L., Atari, M., **Kennedy**, **B.**, Portillo-Wightman, G., Gonzalez, E., Delong, N., Bhatia, R., Mirinjian, A., Ren, X., & Dehghani, M. (2019). Reporting the Unreported: Event extraction for analyzing the local representation of hate crimes, In *Proceedings of the 2019 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and 9th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing (EMNLP-IJCAI).*
- Courtland, M., Mostafazadeh Davani, A., Reyes, M., Yeh, L., Leung, J., **Kennedy**, **B.**, Dehghani, M., & Zevin, J. (2019a). Modeling performance differences on cognitive tests using lstms and skip-thought vectors trained on reported media consumption., In *Proceedings of the Third Workshop on Natural Language Processing and Computational Social Science (NLP+CSS).* Attps://www.aclweb.org/anthology/W19-2106.pdf
- Courtland, M., Mostafazadeh Davani, A., Reyes, M., Yeh, L., Leung, J., **Kennedy**, **B.**, Dehghani, M., & Zevin, J. (2019b). Subtle differences in language experience moderate performance on language-based cognitive tests, In *Proceedings of the 41st Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society, Austin, Texas. Cognitive Science Society.*\*https://cogsci.mindmodeling.org/2019/papers/0280/0280.pdf
- Mostafazadeh Davani, A., Atari, M., **Kennedy**, **B.**, Havaldar, S., & Dehghani, M. (2020). Hatred is in the Eye of the Annotator: Hate speech classifiers learn human-like social stereotypes, In *Proceedings of the 42nd Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society*.
- **Kennedy**, **B.**, Carrazza, M., Rasin, A., Furst, J., & Raicu, D. (2015). Applying association rule mining to semantic data in the lung image database consortium, In *Proceedings of the 15th IEEE International Conference on Data Mining Workshop, ICDMW 2015.*

#### **Journal Articles**

- Hoover, J., Portillo-Wightman, G., Yeh, L., Havaldar, S., Mostafazadeh Davani, A., Lin, Y., **Kennedy**, **B.**, Atari, M., Kamel, Z., Mendlen, M., Moreno, G., Park, C., Chang, T., Chin, J., Leong, C., Leung, J., Mirinjian, A., & Dehghani, M. (2020). Moral Foundations Twitter Corpus: A Collection of 35k Tweets Annotated for Moral Sentiment. *Social Psychological and Personality Science*.
- Garten, J., **Kennedy**, **B.**, Hoover, J., Sagae, K., & Dehghani, M. (2019). Incorporating Demographic Embeddings Into Language Understanding. *Cognitive Science*, 43(1). 6 https://doi.org/10.1111/cogs.12701
- Garten\*, J., **Kennedy**\*, **B.**, Sagae, K., & Dehghani, M. (2019). Measuring the Importance of Context when Modeling Language Comprehension. *Behavior Research Methods*, 51(2), 480–492.
- Hossain, K., Gao, S., **Kennedy**, **B.**, Galstyan, A., & Natarajan, P. (2018). Forecasting violent events in the Middle East and North Africa using the Hidden Markov Model and regularized autoregressive models. *Journal of Defense Modeling and Simulation*.

#### **Skills**

Programming | Experienced: Python, R

Capable: C++, sql, Java, PHP, JavaScript

Python libraries pandas numpy scikit-learn nltk spacy gensim tensorflow keras pytorch transformers

optuna matplotlib seaborn pytest

R packages | tidyverse stats lme4 MASS

Miscellaneous Skills TFX, Git, Vim, MS Office, Google Suite, Markdown, Beamer

#### Software and Data Resources

Neural Text Analysis Pipeline (NTAP)

Lead designer & developer of a Python package for high-level interface for applying modern NLP techniques for text analysis (https://pypi.org/project/ntap/).

Gab Hate Corpus (GHC) Lead author for defining "hate-based rhetoric" and typology used for labeling 27,000 social media posts (https://osf.io/edua3/).

## **Employment History**

5/2019–5/2020, 12/2020–present 1/2018–5/2018, 8/2018–5/2019

> 8/2016–12/2017 6/2015–9/2015

Research Assistant, Department of Psychology, USC

■ Teaching Assistant, Computer Science Department, USC

Research Assistant, Computer Science Department, USC

**Research Experience for Undergrads (REU),** Depaul University

## **Teaching Assistantships**

Applied Machine Learning

Grading, lectures, and content creation. Material: ISLR and Deep Learning with R (*Fall 2020*)

Data Structures & Object Oriented Design

Object-oriented principles, recursion, search trees, graph algorithms in C++ (*Summer 2020*)

Artificial Intelligence

Search, knowledge representation, logic to computer science upperclassmen (*Spring 2019*)

Intro to Programming

Programming concepts and object-oriented programming in C++ (Spring 2018, Fall 2018)

## References

Available on Request